crazyfree.com.au 2019-03-02

# CrazyFree - Privacy Policy

### About Crazy Free

Crazy Free (Cohort Australia Pty Ltd ABN: 54600161386 and its UK subsidiary Cohort Global Limited CN: 07305185 & ICO: ZA059079) provides permission based marketing services to major high street and online brands. We provide a service designed to deliver sales leads from consumers who have consented to be contacted.

Crazy Free has wealth of lifestyle and demographic data that we collect directly and openly from consumers. We do this by publishing a variety of online consumer surveys and conducting a range of permission based direct mail and telemarketing activity on a range of different websites. Crazy Free allows consumers to engage with specific brands or categories of products and services they have indicated they wish to hear from. Crazy Free provides a range of other services to companies using our database.

One of Crazy Free’s key business objectives is commitment to open and transparent information practices – informing individuals about how we collect and use personal information and protect the information privacy of those individuals. Personal information is information about an identified individual or one who is reasonably identifiable.

Crazy Free complies with the AU Privacy Act 1988 including the AU Privacy Principles and other AU regulations such as the AU Do Not Call Register Act 2006, the AU Spam Act 2003, UK Data Protection Act 1998, General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR) and the (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 which govern how it must handle personal information (Privacy Act). Our Privacy Policy explains how we do this. For UK residents to find out more information about your rights around the data protection act and GDPR please visit [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/).

Crazy Free may change the Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and privacy regulation. Any changes will come into effect when an updated Privacy Policy is posted to our website.

### How and what personal Information we collect, and why

#### Direct Collection

Crazy Free collects personal information from individuals when they respond to one of our surveys or competitions or when they request further information from an advertiser. We collect personal information about you, your contact details, your interests, lifestyle preferences, subjects about and persons from whom you may like to receive communications and information, your interactions and communications with us including your participation in competitions and surveys.

#### Indirect Collection

We may also collect information via technology including cookies (see full Cookie Policy) about you from our websites when you visit which is added to your details if we have collected them and which is used in conjunction with the other information about you, including for enhancing your experience.

A cookie is a small piece of computer code which remains on your computer and contains information which helps us identify your browser and previous information viewed in relation to our service. When you visit our websites the cookie records certain details including the date, time and advertising content of that site. The information we collect in this way may include your Internet service provider’s address, date and time of your visit, Pages accessed and type of browser used.

If you do not want us to use cookies then you can easily stop them, or be notified when they are being used, by adopting the appropriate settings on your browser. If you do not allow cookies to be used, some or all of our website might not be accessible to you.

We may collect information about you from someone else but we will take reasonable steps to ensure you are aware of the information collected and the circumstances of collection.

#### Anonymous Third Party Cookies

When you visit our websites and you register or sign up we may set an anonymous third party cookie on your browser. When this cookie is set, all information that would make it personally identifiable is removed. The anonymous third party cookies allow advertisers to target or customise their online advertisements.  

### Why we collect Personal Information and what is it used for?

Crazy Free use the personal information we collect for various purposes, including:

  1. to send you information, offers and promotions about products and services based on your preferences and any prize notifications (Offers) by mail, phone/SMS/MMS or email;
  2. in information products and information management services provided to clients and to assist clients to manage consumer information and strengthen communications between consumers, businesses and service providers;
  3. to administer our database of personal information including improving and personalising Offers, verifying and assessing your identity, maintaining and updating records, developing new products and services;
  4. to enable brands and advertisers you select to communicate with you;
  5. to provide information to third parties to enable them to give you Offers and additional information;
  6. to improve the quality and quantity of information on our websites; and
  7. for statistical and marketing analysis and analytics.
  8. Third Party communication may be from the following categories; Astrology, Charity, Competition Sites, Daily Deals, Financial, Gambling, General Marketing, Personal Injury,  Shopping, Subscription, Survey, Telecommunication, Travel, Utilities.

#### 

How do I unsubscribe?

You may opt-out of receiving any Offers and information from Crazy Free at any time simply by submitting a request in writing or under the relevant Offer or communication to [consumercare@cohortglobal.com](mailto:consumercare@cohortglobal.com?subject=Please%20Unsubscribe). You can opt out of receiving any Offers and information from a third party to whom we provide your information under the relevant Offer or communication, from that third party.

#### To whom do we disclose the Personal Information?

We disclose personal information to our clients and advertisers, third party agents, service providers and contractors only for purposes consistent with the reasons for collecting the information set out in this Privacy Policy.

Some of the recipients of the personal information, including some of our service providers, are based overseas, in a wide variety of countries (including NZ, US, EU, Philippines, India and South Africa). Before we disclose personal information to local or overseas recipients we take reasonable steps to ensure they have privacy practices that are at least as protective as the AU Privacy Principles and the General Data Protection Regulation 2018\. You consent to the disclosure of your personal information on that basis.

We may disclose personal information to any person or authority where we are required to by law.

Other than set out in our Privacy Policy, we will not disclose your personal information without your prior consent.

#### Our security and retention policies

Crazy Free is committed to ensuring security of personal information it holds. Your data is stored in secure servers within your region and we implement a range of measures to protect personal information from misuse, interference and loss, and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Crazy Free holds personal information electronically and in hard copy form, with the assistance of our service providers including the use of secure enterprise grade servers to store personal information.

If Crazy Free no longer needs your personal information we will take steps to destroy or de-identify it – although we may need to retain certain records to meet our legal requirements.

Crazy Free notes that it does not have control over information while in transit over the Internet and it cannot guarantee security of personal information during transmission over the Internet. As well, our web site may include web links to other websites. We are not responsible for and do not endorse the content of those other websites or their privacy practices. We recommend you review the privacy policies of those websites.

#### How to access, correct or delete your Personal Information

Crazy Free works to ensure that all personal information about you that we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. Primarily, we do this by collecting information directly from you.

If you:

  * want to obtain access to any personal information that we hold about you, or
  * believe any of your personal information that we hold is inaccurate, incomplete or it is not necessary to hold it; or
  * want to delete your personal information from our database,

you can contact us on one of the channels below, and we will use reasonable efforts to resolve your request within 30 days.  
We are required to provide our reasons if we refuse your request and, if you disagree, you are entitled to ask us to make a note of the request with your information. We may charge a reasonable fee to cover our costs of responding to your information requests.

#### Cookie Policy Full Policy

A cookie is a small text-only file which is stored on your computer or mobile device when visiting a website to help it function or to track your visits. Our website requires cookies to work correctly. By opting-in to the website you agree to the use of cookies. Further information can be obtained at www.addaboutcookies.org. The table below explains the cookies that are used.

Cookie | Name | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _ga  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmv  
__utmz | These cookies allow us to collect information about how visitors use the website. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. Click here for an overview of privacy at http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html  
Google Adsense | __gads  
_drt_  
id | Google uses cookies to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times a given ad is shown to you. When you visit a website, view an ad, or click an ad supported by Google’s advertising services, Google may set a cookie on your browser. This advertising cookie will appear in your browser as coming from the domain “doubleclick.net”.Learn more about Googles Policies at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/  
Kentico |  | Our website platform using the content management system Kentico which uses cookies to deliver site functionality.  
  
### Australian Office

  * [consumercare@cohort.com.au](mailto:consumercare@cohort.com.au?subject=CrazyFree); or
  * 1300 257 528; or
  * Crazy Free, Consumer Care Department, PO Box 369, Strawberry Hills, NSW, 2012.

### UK Office

  * [consumercare@cohortglobal.com](mailto:consumercare@cohortglobal.com?subject=CrazyFree); or
  * 0203 949 4800; or
  * Crazy Free, Consumer Care Department, 25 Buckingham Palace Road, Level 2, Warwick House,  
Westminster, London, SW1W 0PP.
  * You can contact the Data Protection Officer on: [dpo@cohortglobal.com](mailto:dpo@cohortglobal.com?subject=CrazyFree%20-%20DPO%20Enquiry).

We will respond to you to discuss any concerns within 2 working days of receipt of your e-mail , call or correspondence.

**Cohort Australia Pty Ltd  
Suite 15.04, Ernst & Young Centre, 680 George Street  
Sydney NSW 2000**

**Cohort Global Limited  
25 Buckingham Palace Road, Level 2, Warwick House,  
Westminster, London, SW1W 0PP.**

 **Policy Created: 27th August 2015  
Policy Updated: 22nd May 2018**
